<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Planet Plone</title>
	<link>http://planet.plone.org/</link>
	<language>en</language>
	<description>Planet Plone - http://planet.plone.org/</description>

<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: how to fix &quot;Error: Couldn't install: lxml 3.4.4&quot; with Plone 5.0 unified installer on Mac OS X 10.11.1 El Capitan</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-fix-error-couldnt-install-lxml-3-4-4</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-fix-error-couldnt-install-lxml-3-4-4</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: How to make portal_actions use a popup window</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-make-portal_actions-use-a-popup-window</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-make-portal_actions-use-a-popup-window</link>
	<description>...like the contact-info action</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: Securing Plone Sites With Nginx and HTTPS/SSL</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/securing-plone-sites-with-nginx-and-https-ssl</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/securing-plone-sites-with-nginx-and-https-ssl</link>
	<description>a temporary addition to the official Plone documentation</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 17:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: robot testing error &quot;Non-existing setting&quot;</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/robot-testing-error-non-existing-setting</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/robot-testing-error-non-existing-setting</link>
	<description>&quot;Test case name cannot be empty.&quot;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 01:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Django Under The Hood</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/django-under-the-hood</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/django-under-the-hood</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Bijgewerkt: zaterdag 20:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De donderdag begon met een presentatie van Jacob Kaplan-Moss over HTTP. Hoe gaat Django om met een HTTP-request? Hoe rolt daar een response uit? Hij gaf diverse plekken aan waar een ontwikkelaar voor een klant-applicatie kan &quot;inprikken&quot; op de bestaande Django-techniek. In het voorbijgaan schetste hij ook de ontwikkeling van de techniek; de keuzes die daarin gemaakt zijn en hoe die uitgepakt zijn. Een interessante talk van iemand zowel in techniek als in presentatie goed thuis is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vervolgens sprak Ola Sitarska over Django's admin-interface. Zij gaf aan hoe je deze naar je hand kunt zetten en wat de diverse plekken zijn om dit het handigst te doen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als laatste sprak Iacopo Spalletti over DjangoCMS, een content management-systeem gebouwd op Django. Hij besprak de designkeuzes die zijn gemaakt, vooral met betrekking tot het installeren van plugins. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vrijdag begon met een goede kop filterkoffie en een keynote van Russell Keith-Magee, een van de de actievere ontwikkelaars van de laatste tijd. Aan de hand van Django's commit messages vanaf het eerste uur gaf hij commentaar bij de ontwikkeling. Een centrale vraag was hoe je een groeiende community gezond houdt. Aan de hand van de verhalen bij de commits kon Russell met veel humor hierover vertellen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De volgende presentatie ging over &quot;expressions&quot;. Dit is een manier om ingewikkelde queries op de database te doen. Josh Smeaton is een SQL-expert die relatief nieuw is in Django. Hij legde uit hoe je met F()-expressions dingen kunt doen die tot dusverre vaak werden opgelost met minder robuuste (bijvoorbeeld database-specifieke) technieken. Deze en andere expressions worden uitgelegd op &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.8/ref/models/expressions/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Django Expressions reference&quot;&gt;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.8/ref/models/expressions/&lt;/a&gt; De implementatie is in Django 1.8 ingrijpend aangepast en daardoor sneller gemaakt, met dank aan Josh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amber Brown sprak over Twisted en Django. Dit is een mogelijkheid om asynchrone operaties makkelijker te maken in Django. Ze schetste een simpele patch in DJango die dit mogelijk maakt, waardoor onder andere een veel hogere performance mogelijk wordt. Haar presentatie staat op &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/hawkowl/django-and-twisted-django-under-the-hood-2015&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Presentatie Amber Brown op Speakerdeck&quot;&gt;https://speakerdeck.com/hawkowl/django-and-twisted-django-under-the-hood-2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Aylett vertelde over static files. Het ging dan vooral over CSS en Javascript. Vele soorten pipelines kwamen aan bod. Node.js is hier leidend in, er zijn verschillende oplossingen mogelijk. Django moet daar geen keuze in maken, omdat het veld sterk verandert. Zijn voorstel is de staticfiles-module te promoveren tot een core-module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django security was een presentatie met diverse beveiligingstips voor Django-programmeurs. Florian Apolloner raadde ons aan vooral mark_safe(json.dumps()) te gebruiken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De laatste presentatie van de dag was Documentation systems van Eric Holscher. Hij legde het hoe en waarom uit van &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://readthedocs.org/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Read The Docs&quot;&gt;https://readthedocs.org/&lt;/a&gt;. Dit leunt op het gebruik van Sphinx. Semantische markup (RST) is beter is dan markdown. Hij vertelde hoe je het kunt integreren met je code-module, zonder je zorgen te hoeven maken over de weergave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'s Avonds was er een feest voor alle conferentiegangers. Tijdens dit feest werden er door diverse sprekers lightning talks gepresenteerd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zaterdag waren er ongeveer 120 mensen verzameld in het kantoor van &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://travelbird.nl/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Website TravelBird&quot;&gt;TravelBird&lt;/a&gt;, dat haar ruimte, bureaus en schermen ter beschikking stelde voor de sprint. Er werd gewerkt aan diverse onderwerpen: de admin-interface, het static files-verhaal, expressions, en andere thema's van de lezingen kwamen terug. Er waren workshops over documentatie schrijven en deployment op Heroku. Ikzelf heb me bezig gehouden met openstaande issues in Wagtail. De oorspronkelijke bedenker van Wagtail, Matt Westcott, was ook aanwezig dus dat maakte het overleg makkelijk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al met al een goed georganiseerde en technisch waardevolle conferentie. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dit was de conferentie live op Twitter:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/djangounderthehood&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Twitter hashtag djangounderthehood&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/hashtag/djangounderthehood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/duth&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;Twitter hashtag duth&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/hashtag/duth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: PloneConf 2015</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ploneconf-2015</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ploneconf-2015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Met vier man bezochten we de conferentie. Thijs en Ludolf volgden maandag en dinsdag een training, om op de hoogte te zijn van de nieuwste technieken in Plone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Een lightning talk&quot; class=&quot;image-right&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/DSC_0061.JPG&quot; title=&quot;Een lightning talk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De conferentie stond voornamelijk in het teken van de voornaamste ontwikkeling van dit jaar: de release van Plone 5. Vanaf de keynote-presentatie was al duidelijk dat een grote mijlpaal is: sneller, mooier, sterker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ook gelanceerd is Plone Intranet. Dit is een sociaal intranet met vele eigenschappen die in het moderne samenwerken nodig zijn. Het is ontwikkeld door samenwerkende Europese Plone-partijen en munt uit door een uitermate doordachte gebruikerservaring. Hiermee heeft Plone nu een zeer concurrerend, off-the-shelf intranet-product in huis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dit jaar is &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://plone.com&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;plone.com&lt;/a&gt; gelanceerd, ons visitekaartje naar het bedrijfsleven. Het doel is Plone op professionele wijze te presenteren aan beslissers. De &quot;oude&quot; site &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://plone.org&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;plone.org&lt;/a&gt; blijft dienst doen als portaal voor ontwikkelaars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoe divers Plone is werd duidelijk door de over uiteenlopende onderwerpen van de presentaties: van media-publishing tot urenregistratiesysteem, Plone wordt op allerlei manieren ingezet. Een praatje als &quot;Hoe houden we Plone veilig, maar toch ook flexibel&quot; sprak dan ook veel mensen aan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er werd gediscussiëerd over diverse onderwerpen, zoals bijvoorbeeld &quot;waar willen we staan over vijf jaar&quot;. Dit werd gestructureerd in zogenaamde &quot;open spaces&quot; waar iedereen mag aanschuiven: de Plone-community vergadert niet achter gesloten deuren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daarnaast presenteerden diverse ontwikkelaars handige technieken en wisselden ervaringen uit. De discussies gingen vaak buiten kantooruren verder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vrijdag werd afgesloten met de plenaire vergadering van de Plone Foundation. Deze stichting beheert en beschermt het merk Plone, zodat het product Plone niet afhankelijk is van één bedrijf. Tijdens de vergadering werd het nieuwe bestuur voor het komende jaar gekozen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De laatste twee dagen werd er &quot;gesprint&quot;: Degenen die dit wilden verdeelden zich over diverse teams om gericht aan een bepaalde taak te werken. Zo is zaterdag de documentatie van Plone 5 verbeterd, is er gewerkt aan de vernieuwing van site plone.org en is er een upgrade-handleiding om extra plug-ins geschikt te maken voor Plone 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We kijken terug op een mooie conferentie, en we kijken uit op een zonnige toekomst voor Plone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: plone.api 1.4</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-api-1.4</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-api-1.4</link>
	<description>&lt;h2&gt;What has changed in version 1.4?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Link integrity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plone.api.content.delete now support the parameter &lt;span&gt;check_linkintegrity. This raises an exception if deleting the object(s) would result in broken links.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;kwargs for plone.api.content.transition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;plone.api.content.transition now accepts kwargs that can be supplied to the workflow transition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;from plone import api
portal = api.portal.get()
api.content.transition(obj=portal['about'], transition='reject', comment='You had a typo on your page.')
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tuple support in content.find for &lt;span&gt;object_provides&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span&gt;object_provides parameter allows a tuple of interfaces, as well as a list.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All commits: &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/compare/1.3.3...1.4&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/compare/1.3.3...1.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Changelog: &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/blob/1.4/docs/CHANGES.rst&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/blob/1.4/docs/CHANGES.rst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to ale-rt, neilferreira and pbauer!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 08:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: The open horizon</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/the-open-horizon</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/the-open-horizon</link>
	<description>11 years of Plone at UW Oshkosh, and now a new start</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 11:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>T. Kim Nguyen: How to make URLs clickable in PloneFormGen field help text</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-make-urls-clickable-in-ploneformgen-field-help-text</guid>
	<link>http://designinterventionsystems.com/blog/how-to-make-urls-clickable-in-ploneformgen-field-help-text</link>
	<description>Plone description fields and PloneFormGen field help text are plain text, not rich text (HTML). Here's how to make URLs they contain clickable.</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 11:19:26 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: plone.api 1.3.3 released</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-api-1-3-3-released</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-api-1-3-3-released</link>
	<description>&lt;h2&gt;What has changed in version 1.3.3?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; has been cleaned and updated!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Plone 5 compatibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plone.api is now compatible with Plone 5. This includes registry based mail settings.&lt;br /&gt;Note: The Plone 5 test setup uses plone.app.contenttypes instead of Archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Find content objects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/content.html#find-content-objects&quot;&gt;plone.api.content.find&lt;/a&gt; wraps the portal_catalog tool. It packs a bit of convenience that cleans up your code quite a bit.&lt;br /&gt;The 'context' argument is used to construct the 'path' query:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;# new&lt;br /&gt;find(context=context)&lt;br /&gt;# old&lt;br /&gt;catalog(path='/'.join(context.getPhysicalPath()))&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interfaces' __identifier__ is automatically used for the 'object_provides' argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;# new&lt;br /&gt;find(object_provides=IContentish)&lt;br /&gt;find(object_provides=[IATDocument, IDexterityItem])&lt;br /&gt;or find(object_provides=IContentish.__identifier__)&lt;br /&gt;# old &lt;br /&gt;catalog(object_provides=IContentish.__identifier__)&lt;br /&gt;catalog(object_provides=[IATDocument.__identifier__, IDexterityItem.__identifier__])&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Products.PrintingMailHost support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plone.api.portal.send_email no longer raises ValueError('MailHost is not configured.') when Products.PrintingMailHost is installed and active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Support Zope users in env.adopt_user.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/env.html#switch-user-inside-a-block&quot;&gt;plone.api.env.adopt_user&lt;/a&gt;(username='zope_admin') now works as expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;get_registry_record lists a subset of registry keys on error.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/portal.html#get-plone-app-registry-record&quot;&gt;plone.api.portal.get_registry_record&lt;/a&gt; no longer lists all registry keys. It now lists only keys that contain the passed in record name, instead of all 1500+ keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Revoking user roles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/user.html#revoke-roles-from-user&quot;&gt;revoke_roles&lt;/a&gt; method: now if is't called with obj parameter, it doesn't set inherited roles locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get View&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/content.html#get-view&quot;&gt;plone.api.content.get_view&lt;/a&gt; no longer swallows exception. This means that get_view no longer raises InvalidParameterError when there's an error in the view's __init__.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deleting multiple objects at once&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/content.html#delete-content&quot;&gt;plone.api.content.delete&lt;/a&gt; now accepts a list of objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Products.Archetypes is o&lt;span&gt;ptional &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;plone.api now can be used without Products.Archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Default value for plone.api.content.get_state&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://docs.plone.org/external/plone.api/docs/api/content.html#plone.api.content.get_state&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;plone.api.content.get_state&lt;/a&gt; now allows for an optional default value. &lt;span&gt;This is used when no workflow is defined for the object.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;# new&lt;br /&gt;state = get_state(obj=context, default=None)&lt;br /&gt;if state is None:&lt;br /&gt;    # Do something&lt;br /&gt;# old&lt;br /&gt;try:&lt;br /&gt;    state = get_state(obj=context)&lt;br /&gt;except WorkflowException:&lt;br /&gt;    # Do something &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All commits: &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/compare/1.3.2...1.3.3&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/compare/1.3.2...1.3.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Changelog: &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/blob/1.3.3/docs/CHANGES.rst&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/plone/plone.api/blob/1.3.3/docs/CHANGES.rst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to cekk, jensens and pbauer for making this release possible!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 12:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Make it beautiful</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/anniversary-sprint</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/anniversary-sprint</link>
	<description>&lt;p class=&quot; &quot;&gt;This week we welcome 30 sprinters to our office, the eight Four Digits and our frequent Seats2Meet guests. Up to 50 people on the office? Not a problem at all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a Sprint?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic idea of a Plone Sprint is to get a large group of people together at one location and let them work for a week on Plone features. This makes it easier to communicate complex ideas and write complex code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;anniversary sprint people working&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/anniversary-sprint-people-working.jpg/@@images/6f524ced-681b-43f9-a91c-40bc006554f1.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;anniversary sprint people working&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics defined for this sprint are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plone 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restful API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plone Intranet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;All sprinters can join a group and the group will work on different sets of work to be done to create an end product. The main goal is: 'Make it beautiful'.&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why Sprint?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a sprint you have direct contact with community members, as well as time to work on things. This can be small issues or big complex sub products like the new toolbar in Plone 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;anniversary sprint philip at piano&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/anniversary-sprint-philip-at-piano.jpg/@@images/7324ffdd-b16c-4229-825a-4f8e3978def8.jpeg&quot; title=&quot;anniversary sprint philip at piano&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And you can sit anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Four Digits 10th Anniversary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is Four Digits' 10th anniversary! We started small and are now able to organise sprints and conferences like the one in 2012 in Arnhem. We still use Plone a lot and are a big fan of the security model. Here's to Plone 5 and to the next ten years!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 11:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Tokyo symposium, a very Plone event</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/122157975895</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/122157975895</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I had the pleasure to participate in the first Plone symposium held in Asia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It started already on Friday, when we (Eric Steele, Alexander Loechel, Sven Strack and me) were invited into the CMScom offices by the organizers, Takeshi Yamamoto and Manabu Terada. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There, we met other people, like Masami Terada (whom I first met at the Bristol conference) and were treated to some great cakes. All the while having an inspired conversation on the Japanese Plone community, Pycon JP and Pycon APAC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://40.media.tumblr.com/c90d819e14373cf30c237044486fa4e6/tumblr_inline_nqch3skYrJ1r8vzvq_540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later, at a rather nice restaurant, we were joined by more people, including Tres Seaver and several of the other speakers and staff of the Symposium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following morning we headed for Ochanomizu University, who had not only supplied the meeting space, but thoughtfully also some cute turtles and a sleepy red cat to enhance the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://40.media.tumblr.com/70c254bf5bbe97a731e387341ebd4ef3/tumblr_inline_nqch4tTXjw1r8vzvq_540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Symposium itself was astounding, especially when you consider it was the first time it was held. With 67 people participating from as far away as Osaka and beyond and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://plone.jp/plone-symposium-tokyo-2015/schedule&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;wide range of talks&lt;/a&gt;, both in Japanese and English, there was something to be found for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personal highlights:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;meeting the energetic Chiaki Ishida. Apart from effortlessly chairing the high-quality panel on Plone in higher education, she has been instrumental in using and promoting Plone as Learning Management System at her university and beyond. She also works with professor Toru Miura, whose talk on using Plone for improving his lecturing programme impressed with a nice mix of experience and evidence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Max Nakane, a developer who is dependent on assistive technology, gave a great speech on why accessibility matters and where the accessibility of Plone and other systems stand, and what should be improved. Not only that, the next day I had the chance to work directly with him on the Sprint, and identify issues still open for Plone 5.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tres gave what he described as “the least technical talk I ever held”. Yet still, after it, I &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;finally&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; understand where bobo_traverse comes from… I shudder to think what happens if I see more of his technical talks ;-)&lt;br /&gt;With some good storytelling, it emphasized the community values of our tribes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://40.media.tumblr.com/fe28bb6d326d8a08d3e108e94ebd803b/tumblr_inline_nqch5fLQjI1r8vzvq_540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was also the feeling that ran through the day. Not only in lovely details like hand-made Plone cookies but mostly in the talks and in the hallway conversations, this is a community aimed at helping each other. Nice touch also to include talks on other Python frameworks and technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After Lightning talks (always fun, even in a foreign language!) most of us headed for the afterparty at a nearby Izakaya. Where that curious phenomenon happened again: people trying to tell you that their English is not so good, and then conversing with you in super good English…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was fun to meet such a diverse group of people, and see that the “put a bunch of Plone people in a room and good conversations happen” principle is universally applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://36.media.tumblr.com/0a34676af4d43f6d7525a0ca5cabf630/tumblr_inline_nqch5z8Z2K1r8vzvq_540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next day was Sprinting day. Despite knowing that sprinting is not yet as popular as it should be within the Japanese community, a pretty nice number turned up, and we all set out on our various tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As said before, I mostly worked with Max Nagane on accessibility issues. The good news: Plone 5 will be a massive step in the right direction. But obviously, there is still room for improvement. If you want to help, join the Anniversary sprint in Arnhem/NL when you can, or just start working on the relatively &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/Products.CMFPlone/issues/627&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;small list in the metaticket&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day unfortunately it was time already to fly back, feeling a bit sad to leave but very happy to have met the vibrant, kind and knowledgeable Plone Japan community. Of whom I hope to see many again in the future, both inside and outside Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;And who knows, apparently “Tokyo 2020″ is a thing now ;-) &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;tmblr-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://36.media.tumblr.com/465445d6f24fbbe0b4731077d2062d53/tumblr_inline_nqch6gGWpj1r8vzvq_540.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 10:46:43 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: OpenGraph and SEO support for Plone 4</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/opengraph-and-seo-support-for-plone-4</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/opengraph-and-seo-support-for-plone-4</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We just released fourdigits.seo v1.0 to &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/fourdigits.seo/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo on PyPI&quot;&gt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/fourdigits.seo/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;fourdigits.seo brings additional Publisher and Author data support and SEO overrides support in Plone 4.&lt;br /&gt;- The supported platforms for Publisher are Twitter Card, Open Graph and Google Plus.&lt;br /&gt;- The title and description of the login form, registration form and contact form can be overriden.&lt;br /&gt;- Favicon.ico and Apple Touch icons can be set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick feature run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Site wide settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;General / default:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include site name in title (Include the site name in the title tag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site name seperator (Separator used to separate the object title and the site name in the title tag)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose Publication date (Expose publication date in the head)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login Form Title (Title for the login form)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login Form Description (Description for the homepage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register Form Title (Title for the registration form)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register Form Description (Description for the registration form)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact Info Title (Title for the contact info page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contact Info Description (Description for the contact info page)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;callout&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.41.png&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The default settings tab for fourdigits.seo&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.41.png/@@images/bb276b83-9f3e-4ecb-b670-59612b95aca6.png&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo - site wide setting - default&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Social&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publisher information for the major social media providers: Google Plus, Twitter Card and Open Graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google+ Publisher Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose Twitter Card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter Site Account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose Open Graph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Graph fallback image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expose Open Graph Author&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.46.png&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.46.png/@@images/17b12ba3-2fc9-4b02-be11-8ed776eb55d4.png&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Icons:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Favicon url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Touch icon iPhone url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Touch icon iPhone Retina url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Touch icon iPad url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Touch icon iPad Retina url&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.50.png&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.14.50.png/@@images/096a3bc7-6c2c-42a5-9aab-97be8616c3d0.png&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Indexing:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index Login Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index Register Form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index Contact Info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.15.18.png&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.15.18.png/@@images/01744a89-55d4-4321-8c5f-3ea83cf7803f.png&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Per object settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Override meta title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Override meta description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Archive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Snippet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.22.08.png&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150619at15.22.08.png/@@images/ea07c963-352a-4fba-b88b-21f7ddcfe2bf.png&quot; title=&quot;fourdigits.seo - global settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add 'fourdigits.seo' to the eggs section of your buildout.cfg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install 'SEO' using the 'Add-ons' section in the Plone control panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable the 'SEO' behaviour in the 'Dexterity Contect Types' in the Plone Control Panel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: the 'Site wide settings' are available without enabling the behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Reindex speed done by groups</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/reindex-speed-done-by-groups</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/reindex-speed-done-by-groups</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;My problem was easy: when giving user rights using a ReferenceField to a top folder containing 40k objects I could get some coffee and lunch before my action was completed. This due to the fact Plone was reindexing &lt;span&gt;allowedUsersAndRoles&lt;/span&gt; index on every single object in the folder and its sub folders. This would take up to 15 minutes and the action was fired several times a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://ploneintranet.com/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;Plone Intranet&lt;/a&gt; we came across &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/collective/collective.workspace&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;collective.workspace&lt;/a&gt;, a simple implementation based on putting users in groups and giving groups rights on objects. This means all reindexing is done creating a single object, setting rights based on a group. When a user enters or leaves the group &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; objects are reindexed, meaning updating your security model is super quick! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Normal:&lt;br /&gt;- Folder&lt;br /&gt;  - Subfolder&lt;br /&gt;    - Subsubfolder  &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding user X to folder will include folder, subfolder and subsubfolder to be reindexed. Total time will be: (amount of time per object * num. objects).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;New:&lt;br /&gt;- Folder  (groupX)&lt;br /&gt;  - Subfolder  (groupX)&lt;br /&gt;     - Subsubfolder    (groupX) &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;class Folder(Workspace):&lt;br /&gt;    implements(IWorkspace)&lt;br /&gt;    adapts(interfaces.IFolder)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    @property&lt;br /&gt;    def available_groups(self):&lt;br /&gt;        groups = {&lt;br /&gt;            'groupX': ['GroupXRights', ],}&lt;br /&gt;       return groups&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No (re-)indexing is done when a user is added to groupX, because the group's permissions are already indexed. Group membership is global, so this works everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing we had to do was remove all reindexobject calls in my events.py and create an event based on my security model, when to add or remove a member from the groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;br /&gt;# Events&lt;br /&gt;def set_groups_and_members(context, event):&lt;br /&gt;    # Edit event for all IHasWorkspace&lt;br /&gt; # Sets the members for the groups from the referencefields in context with&lt;br /&gt; # the same name. ie group 'groupX' contains members&lt;br /&gt; # from context.getGroupX()&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; group_memberships = defaultdict(list)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    # Get members for the groups&lt;br /&gt; workspace = IWorkspace(context)&lt;br /&gt;    logger.debug('%s' % workspace)&lt;br /&gt;    for fieldname in workspace.available_groups:&lt;br /&gt;        # Get the accessor and call to get the members&lt;br /&gt;        field = context.schema.get(fieldname)&lt;br /&gt;        for item in set(field.getAccessor(context)()):&lt;br /&gt;            group_memberships[item.getId()].append(field.getName())&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    # add or update members&lt;br /&gt; for memberid, groups in group_memberships.items():&lt;br /&gt;        if memberid not in workspace.members:&lt;br /&gt;            workspace.add_to_team(memberid, groups)&lt;br /&gt;        else:&lt;br /&gt;            membership = workspace[memberid]&lt;br /&gt;            membership.update(dict(groups=groups))&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    # Remove old members&lt;br /&gt; for memberid in set(workspace.members) - set(group_memberships):&lt;br /&gt;        workspace.remove_from_team(memberid)&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 12:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Quick fix for Plone 4.3.x template that’s not mobile-friendly</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/114835735270</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/114835735270</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re running a Plone 4.3.x (and earlier) site, you might have found Google Webmaster tools complaining about mobile friendliness. On inspection, most of that comes from one single template, image_view_fullscreen.pt &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s the one that displays images in their original format when clicked upon, like News images. Many sites will have their own lightbox or jquery popup anyway, but the googlebot still finds the original link.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes three lines to fix this. There’s a pull request already, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/plone/Products.CMFPlone/pull/407&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://github.com/plone/Products.CMFPlone/pull/407&lt;/a&gt; (UPDATE: merged already, thanks Nathan) but if you’re a site administrator you can also change this one in the ZMI. (It’s under ‘portal_skins’, ‘plone-content’, from there you can customize). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you have a theme-product it’s better to override in there, but if you’re not that advanced, you can just use the ‘custom’ folder. I won’t tell ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You do want to address this, as Google will deduct karma points for mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 12:21:30 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Plone Intranet Sprint</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-intranet-sprint</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/plone-intranet-sprint</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;PloneIntranet is een initiatief van een aantal Europese Plone-providers om een modern, sociaal intranet te bouwen. Door een design-first-aanpak te gebruiken kunnen we een goede gebruikerservaring neerzetten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De onderliggende technologie is nog steeds Plone, met al zijn voordelen zoals veiligheid, uitbreidbaarheid en portabiliteit. En nog steeds is alles 100% Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afgelopen week kwamen ontwikkelaars, designers en marketeers samen bij &lt;span class=&quot;link-external&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.syslab.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Syslab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in München. Binnenkort zullen we live gaan met een publieke demo en marketing-informatie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Screenshot homepage PloneIntranet&quot; class=&quot;image-right&quot; height=&quot;241&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ScreenShot20150313at12.46.07.png/@@images/62929749-858e-4fed-9dee-f559d02495cd.png&quot; title=&quot;Screenshot Plone intranet&quot; width=&quot;515&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 14:09:44 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Another film festival, another site</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/112880446740</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/112880446740</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I last wrote on how to create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/18601659838/plone-for-a-film-festival&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Plone site&lt;/a&gt; for my film festival, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rozefilmdagen.nl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roze Filmdagen&lt;/a&gt;, and the Internet has moved on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, in today’s responsive times, this is what I did, given the obvious limitations of &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;zero budget&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;limited time&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;lots of content&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course I started out with Plone, and then added some stuff using add-ons. The ones that are my best-loved friends are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/collective.cover/1.0a10&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;collective.cover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, for easy composite pages. Lovely, works out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/sc.social.like/2.1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sc.social.like&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; because, well, social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/eea.facetednavigation/7.8&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;eea.facetednavigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to create a way &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rozefilmdagen.nl/programma/alacarte&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;people can quickly sort through the programme and find their favorite genre&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/redturtle.imagedevent/1.0.2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;redturtle.imagedevent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as the basic ‘screening’ event. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/ftw.slider/2.1.4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ftw.slider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;to make nice sliders. It’s the cleanest, least intrusive one in my book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then a bunch of behind-the-scenes things to make it nicer to work with, like wildcard.foldercontents and quintagroup.dropdownmenu. Oh, and collective.ptg.contentflow for an awesome ’&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rozefilmdagen.nl/info/geschiedenis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pictorial history&lt;/a&gt;’ effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;So, how to do the pretty-making bits?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, a bit of lending and grabbing here and there. You can find most of it in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/polyester/rfd15.theme&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;theme package&lt;/a&gt;. One of the key things to get right was reconciling collective.cover with the bits of bootstrap I was using (not the whole, but a custom small subset of  bootstrap). Luckily, there is &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/numahell/7928800&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this gist with the correct Diazo rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, you want icons. So &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;fontawesome&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue. And some googlefonts to spice it up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Good, The Bad and the Ugly&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, what’s the experience in total for someone like me, who is not particularly skilled in the art of css?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall: good. The site is clean, was filled up with all content rapidly, and gets positive feedback from the users. Things like Diazo make it super easy to do little things like move the sc.social.like buttons from the top to the bottom, without harming viewletmanagers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bad: I know I shouldn’t, but some things are just easier to do using the ZMI. Yes, I use portal-viewlet-customizations and the 'custom’ folder to insert little things like &amp;lt;i fancyschmansy-icon-class&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;. So sue me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Really ugly: the handling of dates still is a mess. Setting a date format is insanely frustrating: one place for archetypes, one for dexterity, and neither works completely, or without idiotic assumptions that my time format should match my language code. No, it doesn’t and no it shouldn’t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;And somehow, somewhere, somebody thought it was a great idea to embellish every date/time with an annoying little link that shows the time in GMT format. Just so that every screenreader user out there is told: not only do you have a visual impairment, we will go out of our way to break the flow of navigation for you because you probably don’t know which time zone you’re in… Because we’re engineers, and want to be pedantic. Or so. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which leads to painful constructs like &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &amp;lt;span tal:replace=“python:toLocalizedTime(context.start())”&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;                                    Start Date Time&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;                                    &amp;lt;span metal:define-macro=“startdatesame-field-view”&lt;br /&gt;                                      tal:define=“kss_class python:getKssClasses('startDate’,&lt;br /&gt;                                                  templateId=templateId, macro='startdatesame-field-view’);”&lt;br /&gt;                                      id=“parent-fieldname-startDate”&lt;br /&gt;                                      tal:attributes=“class string:$kss_class dtstart;&lt;br /&gt;                                                      title python:context.start().ISO8601()”&lt;br /&gt;                                      &amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;                                    &amp;lt;span tal:replace=“python:toLocalizedTime(context.start(), time_only=1)”&amp;gt;Start Time&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;                                &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Really?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gotchas&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One skeleton in the closet: run Google Webmaster tools on your site, and you will find that it gets very sad, and more than a little upset, about all those semi-automated links to “image_view_fullscreen”. Even if you’re not actually using them, because you catch them with a nice lightboxy one. But the googlebot still sees them. And complains (very rightly so!) about a complete lack of Viewport declarations or any sign that the web has moved on since 1992.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This needs fixing, since it &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; affect your site ranking for mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and one other thing. Really, having just a single favicon.ico is &lt;i&gt;soooo&lt;/i&gt; 2011. What you normally do is get a 256 size PNG, and run imagemagick on it. Or, for the command-line-challenged, &lt;a href=&quot;http://realfavicongenerator.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;use a web service&lt;/a&gt;. But really, we have all the tools already in Plone. This is something the system should handle itself, as a nice gesture. Because we can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But hey, let’s end positive: site delivered, at no cost, and quite well usable on tablets and phones. Hurray for Plone! Now all I need to do is find the right outfit for the Opening Night…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2015 15:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Alpine City Sprint</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/alpine-city-sprint</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/alpine-city-sprint</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Midden in de bergen van Tirol zijn de Plone-ontwikkelaars bezig de volgende release van Plone gereed te maken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er wordt mooie vooruitgang geboekt, zo wordt Plone's meertaligheid verbeterd, oude code wordt verwijderd, en het aantal submodules wordt verminderd. Al deze verbeteringen zullen in Plone 5 gereleased worden. Namens Four Digits is Kees hier aanwezig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De sprint is woensdag begonnen, en loopt nog het hele weekend door.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 16:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Using a webfont to display icons</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/using-a-webfont-to-display-icons</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/using-a-webfont-to-display-icons</link>
	<description>&lt;h2&gt;Creating the vector images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vector images you need for the webfont need to be in the svg format. You can use your favorite editor to create or edit them, I'm using Adobe Illustrator in this example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Creating svg file for webfonts&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/creating-svg-files-for-webfonts.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Creating svg file for webfonts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; &quot;&gt;There is only one thing important when creating the svg files and that is the creation of the &lt;span&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;Artboard&lt;span&gt;”&lt;/span&gt;. The “Artboard” should be exactly 512x512pt. If your image is not square the “Artboard” should still be 512x512pt. After you set the “Artboard” you scale your image to match the height of the “Artboard” and place the image all the way to the left. If some part of your image falls of (like in the example above) or if you have extra space left on the right that is not a problem. Save the file with a lowercase filename without spaces, for example “services.svg”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installing grunt and grunt-webfont&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to install grunt and grunt-webfont is to create a package.json file in your theme product. This file defines all the dependencies and can be used to install those. Here is the package.json file I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;{
    &quot;name&quot;: &quot;fourdigits.theme&quot;,
    &quot;version&quot;: &quot;0.0.1&quot;,
    &quot;description&quot;: &quot;Four Digits Theme&quot;,
    &quot;author&quot;: &quot;Four Digits&quot;,
    &quot;contributors&quot;: [{
        &quot;name&quot;: &quot;Four Digits&quot;,
        &quot;email&quot;: &quot;support@fourdigits.nl&quot;
    }],
    &quot;dependencies&quot;: {
        &quot;grunt&quot;: &quot;~0.4.5&quot;,
        &quot;grunt-contrib-less&quot;: &quot;~0.11.0&quot;,
        &quot;grunt-contrib-watch&quot;: &quot;~0.6.1&quot;,
        &quot;grunt-contrib-uglify&quot;: &quot;~0.6.0&quot;,
        &quot;grunt-webfont&quot;: &quot;~0.4.8&quot;
    },
    &quot;licenses&quot; : [
        {
            &quot;type&quot; : &quot;GPLv3&quot;,
            &quot;url&quot; : &quot;http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-3.0.html&quot;
        }
    ]
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; &quot;&gt;This file should be in the root of your theme package. When the file is created you can install the packages by running:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot; &quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Setting up the Grunt configuration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grunt configuration is stored in the Gruntfile.js which should also be in the root of you theme package. The configuration I used is the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;module.exports = function(grunt) {
  grunt.initConfig({
    webfont: {
      icons: {
        src: 'fourdigits/theme/static/icons/*.svg',
        dest: 'fourdigits/theme/static/fonts',
        destCss: 'fourdigits/theme/static/stylesheets',
        options: {
          font: &quot;icons&quot;,
          hashes: false,
          syntax: &quot;bootstrap&quot;,
          stylesheet: &quot;less&quot;,
          relativeFontPath: &quot;/++theme++fourdigits.theme/fonts&quot;,
          htmlDemo: false
        }
      }
    }
  });

  grunt.loadNpmTasks('grunt-webfont');
&lt;br /&gt;  grunt.registerTask('default', ['webfont']);
};
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span&gt;“src&lt;span&gt;” should contain the location where all your svg images are stored which you created earlier. The “dest” should contain the location of the destination folder for your font. The “destCss” should contain the location of the destination of your stylesheets. The “font” option specifies the name of the font. The “stylesheet” setting specifies which format of stylesheet you want to use, we use less. The “relativeFontPath” should be used to specify the path of the fonts in your website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Generate the font and less file&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate the font and the less file you simply run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;grunt&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output should be something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Running &quot;webfont:icons&quot; (webfont) task
Font icons with 22 glyphs created.

Done, without errors.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; &quot;&gt;In the fonts folder the fonts are created in multiple formats. The files generated are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot; &quot;&gt;icons.eot&lt;br /&gt;icons.svg&lt;br /&gt;icons.ttf&lt;br /&gt;icons.woff &lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot; &quot;&gt;In the stylesheets folder a icons.less file is generated which can be included in your theme or compiled into a css file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Using the icons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the icons from the webfont is really easy. To display an icons simply use the name of the svg file in the classname. For example if your svg icon has the name &lt;span&gt;“&lt;/span&gt;services&lt;span&gt;”, the markup should look like this:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;span class=&quot;icon icon-services&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Since it is a font you can set the color and the size using css, for example:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;.icon-services {&lt;br /&gt; color: &lt;span&gt;#2d9abc;&lt;br /&gt; font-size: 46px;&lt;br /&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a webfont for your icons has a lot of advantages; the images are fully scalable so they look great on retina devices and you save a lot of bandwidth because the webfont file is a lot smaller than individual images. This solution also works crossbrowser (yes, even IE6 ;)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 11:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: PloneConf, the first three days</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ploneconf-the-first-three-days</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/ploneconf-the-first-three-days</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Plone Conf 2014 Group Photo&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/plone-conf-2014-group-photo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Plone Conf 2014 Group Photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://2014.ploneconf.org/&quot;&gt;PloneConf&lt;/a&gt; is a worldwide event held once a year, where Plone stakeholders meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Bristol on Tuesday evening. After checking into our appartments, we went into town for a bite and a drink. Bristol is a lively city, even on a weekday. We soon ran into other Plonistas who had already been doing training and &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://plone.org/events/sprints&quot;&gt;sprinting&lt;/a&gt;. It is great to see all these people again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday was the first conference day. It was a long day, from 9 to 6, packed with talks. Rob did a presentation on the new resource registries story in Plone 5 (with Ramon Navarro Bosch). The list of talks is on &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://2014.ploneconf.org/talks&quot;&gt;ploneconf.org/talks&lt;/a&gt;, and the organisers are doing an excellent job to put these up on &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/channels/ploneconf2014/videos&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt; almost real-time, so it's possible to follow all of it from home. Possible, but not easy! And then, there were Lightning Talks, which is a great way to learn from each other. We announced our &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://plone.org/events/community/anniversary-sprint-2015&quot;&gt;Anniversary Sprint&lt;/a&gt;. We were all rather worn out at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday also featured lots of talks. Maarten did a presentation on the &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://vriendinnenonline.nl&quot;&gt;vriendinnenonline.nl&lt;/a&gt; portal which he built with his partner. Always during lunch and coffee breaks, we discussed Plone-related matters with other Plone people from around the globe, good conversations and new insights are bound to ensue. Thursday ended with the traditional PloneConf dinner and party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was reserved for Open Spaces, where people sit down in smaller groups to discuss things like training, documentation, the roadmap, running Plone in the cloud, the intranet effort, and so on. This is where we come together to find the common ground on which we base our collaboration, which will be mostly remote. It's so valuable to be able to talk to each other and discuss things, it makes communicating remotely later so much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday and Sunday, we sprint. A lot of topics have already been announced, most of them connected to presentations and Open Spaces. We'll see what the weekend brings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Announcing the Anniversary Sprint 2015</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/announcing-the-anniversary-sprint-2015</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/announcing-the-anniversary-sprint-2015</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Plone Anniversary Sprint Logo&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/plone-anniversary-sprint-logo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Plone Anniversary Sprint Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;When and Where&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 - 26 June 2015, Jansbinnensingel 26, 6811AL Arnhem, The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topics will be announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Organizer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four Digits (+31 26 4422700)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Travel info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travelling to Arnhem after a plainride can be done easiest by train. The office is located at walking distance of the Arnhem train station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Schiphol there is a direct train to Arnhem which takes about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Weeze Airport there is a bus (platform 5) from Nijmegen take a train to Arnhem (about 8 an hour). &lt;br /&gt;Alternative From Weeze, take the bus direct to Arnhem Gelredome (EUR 18,-). From there take line 5 or 7 (or any other bus) to the city and get out at “Jansbinnensingel”. From here you can see our office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Eindhoven, take bus 401 to Eindhoven CS (Railway station). From there take one of the following trains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train to Hertogenbosch, from there a train to Arnhem &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Train to Nijmegen, from there a train to Arnhem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or want any please don’t hesitate to contact us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sprint will be held at the Four Digits Office, located in the city centre of Arnhem. We have room for more than enough sprinters. There are a lot of hotels / B&amp;amp;B’s close to the office. If you need any help finding a suitable hotel let us know and we’ll gladly assist you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireless network on a fiber connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sign up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to join us, please sign up for this project, if you want to stay a part of the sprint, please let us know. If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Food&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone can join us for live cooking at the office and breakfast and lunch are included as well for all sprinters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hotels&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hotel Arnhem Centraal”, “Hotel Haarhuis”, “Hotel Molendal”, “Hotel Old Dutch”, “Hotel Blanc”, “Bordeaux B&amp;amp;B”’' and “Hotel Rembrandt&quot; are all within walking distance of our office (Jansbinnensingel 26, Arnhem). If you can't find a suitable hotel let us know and we'll help you find one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coactivate.org/projects/anniversary-sprint/project-home&quot;&gt;CoActivate page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 17:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Verslag Silicon Alley Lightning Talks 26 september</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/verslag-silicon-alley-lightning-talks-26-september</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/verslag-silicon-alley-lightning-talks-26-september</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Zitzakken Concepts 026&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/zitzakken-concepts-026.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Zitzakken Concepts 026&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voor het eerst op een andere locatie, namelijk de conferentieruimte van &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.webiq.nl/&quot;&gt;WebIQ&lt;/a&gt; in het Concepts 026-pand. De samenwerking bracht niet alleen een nieuwe ruimte, maar ook meer diversiteit aan sprekers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Tom Kortbeek Kunstlab Arnhem&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/tom-kortbeek-kunstlab-arnhem.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Tom Kortbeek Kunstlab Arnhem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Kortbeek van &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/kunstlabarnhem&quot;&gt;Kunstlab Arnhem &lt;/a&gt;beet het spits af met “Kunst &amp;amp; Techniek, the next frontier”. Zijn wens (en dat van zijn collega Stefanie Hesseling) is om van een steegje in Arnhem een compositieruimte te maken voor licht en geluid, en deze wereldwijd te verbinden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vervolgens liet Reinier Meenhorst (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.djust.nl/&quot;&gt;DJUST&lt;/a&gt;)  &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://designcode.io/sketch&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; zien, een designtooldie de samenwerking tussen ontwerpers en ontwikkelaars belooft te verbeteren. &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://vizzzion.org/blog/&quot;&gt;Sebastian Kügler&lt;/a&gt; sprak over hoe je platform-onafhankelijk native mobiele applicaties kunt maken met &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://qt-project.org/&quot;&gt;Qt&lt;/a&gt;, en zo de ontwikkelstraat voor complexe projecten aanmerkelijk kunt versimpelen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bonne vertelt en Rob schenkt in&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/bonne-vertelt-en-rob-schenkt-in.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Bonne vertelt en Rob schenkt in&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Na een korte pauze vertelden Bonne Postma en Rob Kerkhoff (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/BaboCoffee&quot;&gt;Babo Koffie&lt;/a&gt;) over de herkomst van koffie, en lieten ze ons een paar bijzondere drankjes proeven. Mirna van der Veen (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/fairtravelers&quot;&gt;IFO Fair Travelers&lt;/a&gt;) legde uit wat ze wil bereiken met Fair Travelers, en wat daarbij komt kijken. Tenslotte kondigde Rob Gietema (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.fourdigits.nl/&quot;&gt;Four Digits&lt;/a&gt;) een &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://arnhemhackathon.nl/&quot;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/a&gt; aan die dit weekend plaatsvond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update (6 oktober): De volgende editie vindt plaats op vrijdag 30 januari.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foto’s door Patrick Kreling (&lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.catharsisdesign.nl/&quot;&gt;Catharsis Design&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Vrijdag 26 september Silicon Alley Lightning Talks</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/vrijdag-26-september-silicon-alley-lightning-talks</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/vrijdag-26-september-silicon-alley-lightning-talks</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;We hebben tot dusverre vijf sprekers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stefanie Hesseling en Tom Kortbeek (Kunstlab Arnhem): “Kunst &amp;amp; Techniek, the next frontier”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinier Meenhorst (DJUST)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bonnie Postma en Rob Kerkhoff (Koffie): “Koffie”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sebastiaan Kügler: “Platform-independent native mobile development using Qt”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mirna van der Veen (IFO Fair Travelers): Fair Travelers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het programma begint om vier uur met inloop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Let op, andere locatie!&lt;/b&gt; We organiseren de Lightning Talks met onze buren van Concepts026, aan Jansbinnensingel 20.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 07:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Four Digits: Upgrading Plone 3.3 to Plone 4.3</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/upgrading-plone-3-3-to-plone-4-3</guid>
	<link>https://www.fourdigits.nl/blog/upgrading-plone-3-3-to-plone-4-3</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we moved a site from a long-time customer to Plone 4.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, the list of step to follow in &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://plone.org/documentation/manual/upgrade-guide/version/&quot;&gt;http://plone.org/documentation/manual/upgrade-guide/version/&lt;/a&gt; were quite exhaustive. There were some things that we did differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went straight from Plone 3.3 to 4.3.3, skipping the intermediate versions (4.0, 4.1 and 4.2). For our site this worked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that, we ran all upgrade steps at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had to manually remove some Javascripts (mostly Kupu) from the registry, in order for TinyMCE to work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Plone 4 vs Plone 3 Performance&quot; class=&quot;image-inline&quot; src=&quot;https://www.fourdigits.nl/images/plone-4-vs-plone-3-performance.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Plone 4 vs Plone 3 Performance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sooner you upgrade to a more recent stable version, the smaller the hassle. Also, there’s a performance improvement (see image), and some nice new features. See &lt;a class=&quot;external-link&quot; href=&quot;http://www.sixfeetup.com/blog/five-reasons-why-waiting-isnt-the-best-upgrade-strategy&quot;&gt;http://www.sixfeetup.com/blog/five-reasons-why-waiting-isnt-the-best-upgrade-strategy&lt;/a&gt; for more reasons to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Stroopwafels &amp; cake driven documentation for Plone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/76124851260</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/76124851260</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend (7-9 feb 2014) the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coactivate.org/projects/stroopwafel-sprint/project-home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stroopwafel sprint&lt;/a&gt; was held in Amsterdam. The idea behind it was to have a ‘meta-sprint’, to organize, strategize and plan for the future of Plone documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out to grow beyond our initial expectations, and much work was done by the participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/987d4b478d8f261fe7ca4ed928e5b72b/tumblr_inline_n0qni7KBRm1r8vzvq.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cake-driven documentation was taken to new heights…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll hear much more about the results in the coming months, and in the run-up to Plone 5. But some of the highlights were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;we have a plan for consolidating all documentation in one place. That includes docs targeted at the various audiences (end-users, themers, site admins, deployers, developers). We’ve killed many post-it notes and colored dots in the process, but now have a mindmap and a plan. Huge thanks go out to Sisi Nutt, for guiding us, and keeping us all on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have a plan for versioning the documentation for the different versions of Plone. This is especially important as Plone5 will bring changes to the user interface. We will be able to have the documentation ready for the version of Plone that users are on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have a clean separation between the actual documentation and the technical aspects (buildouts, testing frameworks) to make it all look good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we have the infrastructure in place, and working, to create multi-lingual versions of the documentation. Translators will be able to work with Transifex, to make translating much easier (Thanks, Giacomo Spettoli!) and we will even have automated screenshots in the correct language (Thanks, Asko Soukka!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we’ve worked on selecting a correct license for all documentation (Creative Commons 4.0 by-attribution) to maximize the re-use of documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we’ve identified gaps in the documentation, and a hit-list of wrong, out-of-date, and misleading info that will be taken down, corrected or re-routed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;All in all, a very productive weekend, and more than enough to do before the next Documentation sprint in Munich, Germany. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you read that right: two documentation sprints in a row! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have our eyes set on major improvements for Plone 5, not only the software but also the documentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, as ever, it’s all made possible by the great Plone community. Ten people from six countries worked hard, but also had immense fun doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;thanks to all participants, to the people that helped us remotely, and to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plone.org/donate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Plone Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for supporting sprints like this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 17:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Please, Plone developers, refrain from &lt;dt&gt;</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/52906861322</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/52906861322</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi people, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;last week an absolutely fabulous gathering happened: Plone Symposium Midwest, in Oshkosh, Wisconsin, USA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much happened there, which you will read about in various other places. Especially,  we also did some good work on accessibility. I’ll post much more on this in the coming weeks; stay posted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I want to stress today to the Plone community: we have been using the HTML tags of &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;dd&amp;gt; for a lot of stuff. Most notably portlets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is wrong. Let me repeat this: this is wrong. You should only be using &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt; and consorts if it is actually semantically correct. That means: you can use it if it is actually a definition list. You should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be using this for display purposes. Like, really not. No. Just don’t. Bunnies and kittens will die in vain when you do this. We love bunnies and kittens, and they should thrive. Trust me on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;image&quot; src=&quot;http://38.media.tumblr.com/be1ef6adfd33c72620efc52117fb644d/tumblr_inline_mocy0vho5y1qz4rgp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will change the whole portlet templates in the future. As many people are basing their own templates off of the standard ones, we won’t do this in the Plone 4.x series, so we won’t break your stuff unexpectedly, but we will do it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So please. If you want to future-proof your portlets: use something else. Use a header tag for the header, and use &amp;lt;ul&amp;gt; &amp;lt;li&amp;gt; for the content. Tack classes onto it so the design people can make it beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just don’t use &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt; and friends, unless your portlet is actually, semantically, really, seriously, and I mean this,  an explanation of a term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using it just to tack some CSS onto it, change your ways. Please, pretty please, with whipped cream on top. It will make our compliance with accessibility rules around the globe much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: PLOG 2013: a very human side of Plone</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/48111596037</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/48111596037</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://opensourcehacker.com/2013/04/08/plog2013-symposium-post-mortem/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Much&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netsight.co.uk/blog/plone-open-garden-2013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;has&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://garbas.si/blog/2013/escaping-april-weather-plog-reportout&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;been&lt;/a&gt; blogged about Plone Open Garden already; the food, the hotel, the location and the great organizing by Abstract can’t be praised enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/7ba5569109617c68af4a67e7617d61fe/tumblr_inline_mlcck6LMvo1qz4rgp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What most struck me, though, was that it was also such a great experience on the human, not coding, side of things. With a manageable number of people present, you could really get to know each and every one (plus, in various cases, their loved ones, both tall &amp;amp; tiny… #goplonegoplone). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was reflected in the sprinting as well; no sooner had two highly interesting talks on &lt;a href=&quot;http://cosent.nl/en/blog/plonesocial-plog2013&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;social&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/ThomasDesvenain/collectivelocal-plog2013-v2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;workspaces&lt;/a&gt; finished, or the authors got together to see if they could combine their work to make for some truly interactive intranet-behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pattern (no pun intented) continued: people were not just developing their own pet projects, but talking to each other to get stuff moving. One example: After @datakurre had &lt;a href=&quot;http://datakurre.pandala.org/2013/04/generate-annotated-screenshots-with.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;proven&lt;/a&gt; he will soon bring about the Robocalypse, when Plone will become self-aware and start to talk to unsuspecting users, he also worked on a proof-of-concept to integrate accessibility testing. &lt;br /&gt;A few days later, we’re still clearing up some licensing issues, but we will very soon have basic a11y testing into the Plone automated testing stack. This is a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; win, especially with things moving forward so fast in the UI department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pool Driven Development also was a keeper. Write documentation, or be thrown in a rather chilly pool. Works a treat!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other highlights for me were a special session with ‘rookies’. A great, hands-on way to ask where new people get stuck, help get them un-stuck on the spot, and engage them in improving the experience for other newcomers. This &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; should be repeated at other Plone events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As should be the 'strategic discussion’. It was late at night, it was unstructured, but with 10+ people present with a wealth of Plone experience it was also very valuable. This one deserves a separate write-up, which I will try to do a bit later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hidden gem: Netsights’ plugin for Single Sign on, cunningly named &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/netsight/netsight.windowsauthplugin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;windowsauthplugin&lt;/a&gt;. Now of course, this is just a little white lie; there is nothing Windows-specific about it, and it will work just as well if you have a Kerberized NFS-4 setup. But let’s not tell the Windows people that the &lt;em&gt;working&lt;/em&gt; part of their AD setups is based on tested Unix technology, now shall we…&lt;br /&gt;In any case, this means we can do more than ever to save the world, and countless unhappy users, from the hell that is Sharepoint and bring them some Plone goodness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/7def2b8466e7569148e2aa3dc40ad453/tumblr_inline_mlcd7egmUi1qz4rgp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much more went on, but these were the highlights for me. Oh, and that Negroni in the harbour of Sorrento, obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, next year again? You bet!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: A recipe for a nonprofit Plone site</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/30599770051</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/30599770051</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;Since a bunch of people asked, here’s a description of the process leading to our new &lt;a href=&quot;http://schonekleren.nl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://schonekleren.nl&lt;/a&gt; website. (Yes, the website is in Dutch, our curious grunting language, but it’s applicable to more…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started out with an old, crappy, user-hostile website. It was based on Joomla, customized to death, not upgradeable, and even posting a simple news item cost half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice for Plone was an easy one, as our intranet runs on it, and we have experience with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting old content out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;transmogrifier to the rescue! We had about 1100 old articles, which we needed to save, if only to condense them into overviews. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now beware, transmogrifier is not for the faint-of-heart. It’s a powertool, with fast-moving sharp blades. You don’t need much knowledge of Plone, but a lot of generic sysadmin knowledge to make it work, and usually some dabbling in SQL. I’m a sysadmin so managed fine, but most nonprofits don’t have one. If you can, outsource this to your local friendly service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plone products used&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new site runs Plone 4.2, and the following add-ons. Quite a lot, but most of them are sort of necessary…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;diazo. In our case, coupled with diazotheme.bootstrap. Yep, that’s twitter’s bootstrap, which does all kinds of dark css magic to keep it responsive and mostly working on IE. I don’t know a lot about CSS, so gladly tagged along with current best practice. It also leverages webcouturier.dropdownmenu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the usuals: PloneFormGen, collective.quickupload, wc.pageturner, collective.embedly to take the pain out of embedding media, and various fun portlets. Oh, and Doormat, obviously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.easyslider. Great fun, and just needs some extra CSS which even I can provide to do fancy overlays for the front page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ContentWellPortlets. Yes, Deco is just round the corner, but we needed a solution right now. And it does uninstall cleanly, so when Deco is around we can move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.megaphone for petitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pcommerce for our little webshop. For a small shop, this is all you need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the brilliant eea.* set of products. eea.tags for sane tags, eea.facetednavigation for a nice interface to loads of docs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;icing on the cake: unweb.iptc to automagically extract tags from photos, collective.routes to do cool stuff with URL’s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pet peeves remaining:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having to use collective.contentleadimage in this day and age is just a shame. It works, and works great. It is also needed. Try explaining to editors that NewsItems can have an image that shows up in content listings, but Pages can’t. You can’t and you shouldn’t have to. &lt;br /&gt;But there are inconsistencies with setting image sizes with the regular NewsItem. And customizing the NewsItem views is a royal pain in the lower backside. &lt;br /&gt;Really, ContentLeadImage functionality should so go into core. Like yesterday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is some confusion between new and old style Collections. Not all add-ons can use the new ones, and having both enabled confuses the editors. So down to the old ones for now. Hoping this will pass with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big wins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;happy editors. Like, very happy editors. They now can update the site completely without technical assistance. This is a big win. A huge win. It means we can get back to our job, which is improving the lives of underpaid garment workers around the world. Not struggling with a CMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;happy supporters. They like our site. A lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, all in all, a succesful project, run on a budget of (ahum) 0 euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Would I recommend this to other nonprofits? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, first fight for more budget. You’ll get it done sooner, and better, with your local trusted Plone service provider. Doing the import of old content is definitely something you’re better off outsourcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if push comes to shove, and you’re faced with the choice of having to stick with inferior CMS’s or move to Plone, it can be done on a budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure your webteam collects all the happy reactions from users and editors, and use that as ammo to get more budget next year. Then you can hire more professional help, and get to do the fun stuff yourself. Like save the world. And the cheerleader (M/F).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 19:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: I've finally done it...</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/25582826925</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/25582826925</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;An improvement on the Long Island Ice Tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It tastes of grapefruit soda. Obviously, it contains neither grapefruit nor soda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I call this the Polyester Pushover.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part vodka&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part tequila&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part white rum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part triple sec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part gin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1 part lemon juice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;2/3 part Aperol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/3 part Limoncello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shake with ice, fill flute with icecubes, pour to half, top up with champagne.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Think of me in your final moment of bliss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Open source urbanism</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/23479583477</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/23479583477</link>
	<description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://ecosistemaurbano.org/english/open-source-urbanism-open-source-city/&quot;&gt;Open source urbanism&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;p&gt;Interesting read on how the cultural shift of social media can influence how our cities are shaped by the people living there&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 14:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Paul Roeland: Plone for a film festival</title>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/18601659838</guid>
	<link>http://polyrambling.tumblr.com/post/18601659838</link>
	<description>&lt;p&gt;I help organize the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rozefilmdagen.nl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Roze Filmdagen&quot;&gt;Roze Filmdagen&lt;/a&gt;, the Amsterdam Gay &amp;amp; Lesbian Film Festival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the website, we (obviously) use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plone.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Plone&quot;&gt;Plone&lt;/a&gt;, since I’m quite comfortable with that. And, sometimes, when you’ve struggled with more difficult Plone inner workings, it can be a refreshing experience to relive why this is such a great piece of software. Yes, it can be tricky if you try to do complicated stuff with it. It’s a powertool, so it can hurt your fingers. But my oh my, is it quick to get the job done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up the site was a joy, and gave us many things for free: an automatic Ical-compatible feed of all screenings for people with smartphones; the ability to view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rozefilmdagen.nl/programma&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; title=&quot;Programme&quot;&gt;program&lt;/a&gt; in many ways using tags and topics; this way, visitors can easily find the kind of films that they are interested in in the mass of 110 different screenings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested: the site runs on Plone 4.1.3, with the following add-ons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;layout based on v2.theme (rather modified)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Products.Doormat (modified to serve as navigation, rather than ‘doormat’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Products.PloneFormGen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.contentLeadImage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.plonetruegallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.portlet.banners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fourdigits.portlet.twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collective.portlet.relateditems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;and some extras to make life easier for the editors, like collective,quickupload.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It runs on a modest server, with nginx as webserver and varnish as proxy, and can easily cope with a few thousand visitors a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, a pleasant experience, and running nicely. Thank you Plone!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
